<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Goto THAT Conference</title>
  <slug>THAT.CONF</slug>
  <pubDate>2018-11-23 05:07:09</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2018-11-23 05:07:32</lastModified>
  <excerpt>I try and convince you to go to a conference near you</excerpt>
  <content>&lt;h3 id="5fdc" class="graf graf--h3 graf-after--h3" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.015em; margin: 53px 0px 0px -2.13px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 34px; line-height: 1.15;"&gt;About me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="d18b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3" style="margin: 8px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;I identify as a full-stack ASP.net developer that is always trying to learn new things. I have many interests in a lot of different technologies that I would love to know more about. I have never been to a conference before and I just got back from my very first one. The conference I attended was called THAT conference and had many features that I loved. It had open spaces for open conversations and concentration, sessions (kind of like lectures), and tons of bacon of course. In one of the sessions called a keynote, which is a general idea of what and why we were all here for. Part of the talk challenged the audience to do something and then just doing it no matter the result. I challenged myself to complete a blog at the conference and decided to write about my experience. I want to talk about something I might have done differently, what I personally got out of it, advice for other people who are looking for what to do before and at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7f81" class="graf graf--h3 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.015em; margin: 56px 0px 0px -2.13px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 34px; line-height: 1.15;"&gt;What came out of&amp;nbsp;it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ba62" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3" style="margin: 8px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;I personally got a lot out of the whole experience because I kept in mind the reason I was attending, which was personal growth and development. I poured my heart and soul into every moment I could at each and every interval. I took the whole experience very seriously and forced myself to be as uncomfortable as possible. Since I did this I was able to look inside myself to see a few weaknesses, identify some core life questions, and started to take every moment seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2cb7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;So since there is such a diverse culture at the conference I attended there was always a ton to be doing at all times. THAT conference had many sessions to choose from within a certain hour so it was very hard to decide what was best. I did do some pre-planning work into reading what each session was about. What was interesting for me though is I totally changed my mind while I was there. I went to totally different sessions that I planned on going to and purposely attended sessions that would challenge me. I changed my mind a lot because I really asked myself which opportunity was best at a given time. I experimented while I was there and even went to four different sessions in one of the time slots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="47c8" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.012em; margin: 30px 0px 0px -1.63px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 26px; line-height: 1.22;"&gt;Choose your time wisely and challenge how you are using&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="ed32" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4" style="margin: 6px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Since there is so much to do in an hour you really need to consider what you would miss out on by attending one session over another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="599e" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.012em; margin: 30px 0px 0px -1.63px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 26px; line-height: 1.22;"&gt;Have conversations with many different people&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="13bf" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4" style="margin: 6px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;By having many conversations with a lot of the different types of perspective at the conference I learned a lot of things. These conversations were bigger than technology-related issues and focused on things like the human condition. We should embrace talking about the hard things and practice having level-headed conversations about money, religion, and other taboos. The more people you end up talking to the more you realize you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="cad0" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.012em; margin: 30px 0px 0px -1.63px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 26px; line-height: 1.22;"&gt;Write down your thoughts every night a conference goes&amp;nbsp;on&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="e75a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4" style="margin: 6px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Each night you should be writing down your thoughts, even if it is as silly as &amp;ldquo;the bacon was good, I want more&amp;rdquo; This is kind of like a writing prompt, as you start writing you can keep flowing your mind through the ink of your pen and really get down to all the different types of thoughts that happened that day. You might be surprised what you write down, you might even learn something about yourself as I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="9a4b" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.012em; margin: 30px 0px 0px -1.63px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 26px; line-height: 1.22;"&gt;Embrace being&amp;nbsp;human&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="0539" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4" style="margin: 6px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t done for a very long time was going down a water slide and just having a wonderful time. I had such an awesome time partly because I was on this high of adrenaline. It seems so easy to forget that as an adult we are still allowed to have fun, life shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so serious all the time. Take advantage of all the things that make you special and start sharing them with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="58fc" class="graf graf--h4 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.012em; margin: 30px 0px 0px -1.63px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 26px; line-height: 1.22;"&gt;Technology and an eye into the&amp;nbsp;future&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="75f3" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h4" style="margin: 6px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;You talk to so many people at a conference like this you hear a lot of challenges they have day to day. They always say that the grass is greener on the other side. As many of us know that is most likely never the case. It is very hard to know the struggles that everyone is going through themselves. I have learned that no matter which technology stack that was chose, there was still hardships and other things that could always improve. Aim big and plan in small steps so you can fail early on and figure out what not to do so you can grow that much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="f65e" class="graf graf--h3 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.015em; margin: 56px 0px 0px -2.13px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 34px; line-height: 1.15;"&gt;My Advice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0548" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3" style="margin: 8px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Do pre-planning and read descriptions of each and every session to familiarize yourself with everything no matter your own personal interest level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94a7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Ask questions to other people like what was your favorite session, what sessions are you going to next. This way you can learn about a session you didn&amp;rsquo;t go to and you can kind of optimize your time that way (since you have to picky).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9deb" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Always sit at new tables to diversify your experience, don&amp;rsquo;t stick to your same office team and try and branch out as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dccd" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Consider what you are interested in and figure out how to craft questions that will spark a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0d99" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Plan to set time aside to do open session type conversations, you never know what your inner psyche might ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="11f7" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Create a journal of your experiences for each night, think of this like a normal debug log for a program. Instead, it is your life and this way you can look back at what you wrote down and start debugging your thoughts in the current time you wrote things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5b82" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let fear consume you, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of risk. Know that you will fail and embrace it, learn from it and make plans on how you will continue rolling down the hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9863" class="graf graf--h3 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.015em; margin: 56px 0px 0px -2.13px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 34px; line-height: 1.15;"&gt;What would I try differently&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="f734" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3" style="margin: 8px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I made a mistake on how I approached things this time around. One thing I might ask myself if I do decide to go to another conference is: What do I want to accomplish here? Is there anything in particular that I am aiming at. Or is it that I want to learn all the things and talk to all the people. Ask yourself these questions before you are at the conference and you might find a more productive use of your time overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="678b" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Giving people my information to keep in touch. Man, I wish I would have done this more, there was just so many great people here. To explain it this way it seemed like everyone there was family. There was so much love and respect that I witnessed, I felt safe and at home after I got used to being surrounded by so many people at all points at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ef0" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Bring a computer that I can play around with some of the new ideas that I am witnessing. I think maybe not having a computer was a good thing for me this time around since I could focus on myself (which is something I needed) I wasn&amp;rsquo;t distracted by any social media or any form of online &amp;lsquo;waste&amp;rsquo; of time. I think I would like to bring it next time so I can program and show off some cool code in an open circle or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="794b" class="graf graf--h3 graf-after--p" style="font-family: medium-content-sans-serif-font, 'Lucida Grande', 'Lucida Sans Unicode', 'Lucida Sans', Geneva, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: -0.015em; margin: 56px 0px 0px -2.13px; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84); --baseline-multiplier: 0.22; font-size: 34px; line-height: 1.15;"&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7492" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3" style="margin: 8px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;I challenge you to go to THAT conference, have THAT conversation, do THAT thing you always wanted, try THAT new food, try THAT new approach&amp;hellip; well, you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5528" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p" style="margin: 29px 0px 0px; --baseline-multiplier: 0.17; font-family: medium-content-serif-font, Georgia, Cambria, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif; font-size: 21px; line-height: 1.58; letter-spacing: -0.003em; color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.84);"&gt;Challenge yourself to be a kid again, challenge your fears and never settle for stopping to grow as a human being. Review your feelings, and question anything that is on your mind. Talk about hard things like money and ethics. Take your life to the next level and figure out what you really value in life. Make a plan to get to your goals, even if you fail you haven&amp;rsquo;t. You&amp;rsquo;ve made progress to your goals even when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it. You&amp;rsquo;ve learned what NOT to do, empower THAT feeling&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>that</category>
    <category>conference</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>